Pramesh Attwala

User Experience
Design + Development
Leader

pattwala@gmail.com
(647) 300-7104
twitter.com/ttwala
instagram.com/pattwala
linkedin.com/in/prameshattwala

Creating value for clients and customers through design thinking and technology.

A seasoned professional with 18 years of experience producing digital programs and products. At the core, I'm a creator with an entrepreneurial spirit, passionate about working with brilliant people to make digital things that solve real problems for real people.

- · Design leadership
- · Human centered design
- Mentorship to developers and designers
- · Responsive website design
- · Presentations & speaking
- Development leadership
- · Solutions architecting
- Business development
- · Client management
- Project management
- Process improvement
- Workflow optimization
- · Business modeling
- Front-end development
- WordPress development
- · Back-end development
- · Data modeling

Experience

GRNDWRK Inc.

January 2014 - April 2018

Partner + Technical Director

Co-founded GRNDWRK, a boutique user experience design studio in Toronto. Provided end-to-end project leadership, including planning, scoping, client management, project management, execution, and delivery. Optimizing processes between design and development teams to ensure teams could work effectively and efficiently to deliver projects on time and budget.

Clients: TIFF (tiffcanadaonscreen.com), Proof (getproof.com), Allstate Canada (blog.allstate.ca), Orion Travel Insurance, CAA Insurance (broker.caainsurance.com), Camp Walden Canada (campwalden.ca), Grayson Matthews (themusicassembly.com), Catelli (catelli.ca), Boehringer Ingelheim (red-fish.ca), Roche (rewritecancer.ca), Home by Dream (homesbydream.ca), Interac, Jam3, Kijiji, CoFo Design (cofodesign.com)

Pramesh Attwala

January 2010 - January 2014

Freelance User Experience Consultant

Provided user experience design services, including creative design and front-end development, for native apps and website campaigns.

Clients: Camp Walden Canada (campwalden.ca), Orange Paperclip (productofitaly.ca), Spoke Technologies (spokenphotoapp.com), Career Meets Life (careermeetslife.com), Environics Communications, Garrison Health Technology Ventures, Bousfields (bousfields.ca), Marble Media, Ontario Camps Association

Right Spot Media (formerly Commune Media)

August 2009 - September 2011

Creative + Technical Lead

Lead the user experience design and development of various SMB program websites and digital marketing landing page campaigns. Managed off-shore development teams to ensure developed websites adhered to design specifications.

Clients: Cottage Life (formerly Quarto Communications), Enbridge Gas Distribution, Ontario Real Estate Association, ACÉPO, INTERXVENT Canada, Hospitals In-Common Laboratories

Canadian Broadcasting Corporation

May 2003 - July 2009

Interactive Producer

Designed and developed program websites, produced original interactive content features for CBC's Arts and Entertainment department. Lead organizational adoption of Web 2.0 best practices in CSS and JavaScript (JSON and AJAX).

Programs: Rick Mercer Report, Little Mosque on the Prairie, Just For Laughs, Being Erica, Douglas Coupland's jPod, Triple Sensation, Doctor Who, Steven Spielberg's Taken, Toronto Rocks! SARS Benefit Concert, Canadian Country Music Awards, Canadian Urban Music Awards, Brit Awards

AGF Management Ltd.

July 1999 - February 2002

Web Developer

Front-end web developer of financial applications that enabled clients and financial advisors secure, online access to account information.

Education

Product Faculty

July 2018 - August 2018

Product Management Masterclass

Enrolled in the 2018 summer cohort with the goal of acquiring the knowledge, and the toolkit, to effectively develop a clear product strategy and roadmap, adding to my existing skillset of stakeholder relations, effective team management and lean UX practice.

Ryerson University

1996 - 2000

Bachelor of Compuer Science (BSc.)

Learned and applied key fundamentals of computer science: problem solving, algorithms, relational database design, human computer interaction (HCI), networking.